<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nix on Hello, I'm Mark</title><link>https://markc.su/tags/nix/</link><description>Recent content in nix on Hello, I'm Mark</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 09:47:41 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markc.su/tags/nix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up project specific tools using Nix</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/nix-direnv-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 09:47:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/nix-direnv-setup/</guid><description>Over my past blog posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve made it clear that I enjoy how much I like setting up all my projects in the declarative way of Nix. In this article, I will go more in detail on how exactly I have direnv set up to automatically load my tools when I hop into a project.
In my last article I talked about how I don&amp;rsquo;t have most of my programs installed globally, but instead, I have it set up so that whenever I jump into one of my project directories it automatically loads the correct packages and tools into my terminal environment.</description></item><item><title>Nix - The best package manager you should be using</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/nix-package-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 22:21:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/nix-package-manager/</guid><description>This is an article I wrote for the upcoming Visionen issue &amp;ldquo;Nachwuchs&amp;rdquo;. The issue will be released in the coming weeks and this serves as a little sneak-peak.
Have you ever tried to install a program, only for it to require some specific Python version, GCC to be exactly version 11, or some other random program you never even heard of? Additionally, you have to figure out where to install what and how, because everybody has their standard on how programs should be installed.</description></item><item><title>I use NixOS btw</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/nix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 13:36:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/nix/</guid><description>Table of Contents&amp;nbsp;¶ Table of Contents Introduction Fun Study Phase Project Purely functional? What? How do I install a program? Global Install So this is the perfect OS, why doesn&amp;rsquo;t everyone use it? Introduction&amp;nbsp;¶ In the world of Linux distros, there are quite a few unique distros. Just to mention two amazing ones of the bunch: Hannah Montana Linux and Biebian can improve your Linux experience with awesome pre-installed theming.</description></item></channel></rss>