<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming on Hello, I'm Mark</title><link>https://markc.su/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on Hello, I'm Mark</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 09:47:41 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markc.su/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up project specific tools using Nix</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/nix-direnv-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 09:47:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/nix-direnv-setup/</guid><description>Over my past blog posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve made it clear that I enjoy how much I like setting up all my projects in the declarative way of Nix. In this article, I will go more in detail on how exactly I have direnv set up to automatically load my tools when I hop into a project.
In my last article I talked about how I don&amp;rsquo;t have most of my programs installed globally, but instead, I have it set up so that whenever I jump into one of my project directories it automatically loads the correct packages and tools into my terminal environment.</description></item><item><title>I use NixOS btw</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/nix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 13:36:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/nix/</guid><description>Table of Contents&amp;nbsp;¶ Table of Contents Introduction Fun Study Phase Project Purely functional? What? How do I install a program? Global Install So this is the perfect OS, why doesn&amp;rsquo;t everyone use it? Introduction&amp;nbsp;¶ In the world of Linux distros, there are quite a few unique distros. Just to mention two amazing ones of the bunch: Hannah Montana Linux and Biebian can improve your Linux experience with awesome pre-installed theming.</description></item><item><title>React.js Games</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/react_games/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 09:14:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/react_games/</guid><description>React.js Games&amp;nbsp;¶ Recently I was at a hackathon (StartHack 22) and there I did a lot of frontend for the app we produced. I told myself there I&amp;rsquo;ll not write another line of Javascript or CSS for the weeks to come, because I had enough frontend for the time being. Then came the weekend and some people were playing Minesweeper on my Discord bot Lecturfier. The problem with Minesweeper on Discord is though, that the playing field is simply one big field of spoiler-tagged characters, meaning there is no way to actually flag bombs and there&amp;rsquo;s no way for the bot to know if you won or lost.</description></item><item><title>3D Raycasting</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/raycasting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 08:11:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/raycasting/</guid><description>Becoming a Coding Train Fanboy&amp;nbsp;¶ Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been binging a lot of YouTube again and for a while now I&amp;rsquo;ve been recommended The Coding Train videos, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never cared enough to open one of his 40min videos, until a week ago when I discovered how great his coding projects are. Upon watching the introduction of one of his approximating Pi videos I decided it would be fun to try and code the program, before watching the video.</description></item><item><title>Learning the Nimble Nim</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/learning_nim/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 14:38:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/learning_nim/</guid><description>Table of Contents&amp;nbsp;¶ What is Nim? Why? The Surprises Variables Switch Cases For Loops Procedures Arrays Objects Conclusion What is Nim?&amp;nbsp;¶ Nim does a good job explaining what it is in a short way on their website:
Nim is a statically typed compiled systems programming language. It combines successful concepts from mature languages like Python, Ada and Modula.
But that quote only covers a tiny portion of what Nim really is.</description></item></channel></rss>