<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Hello, I'm Mark</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Hello, I'm Mark</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 09:09:47 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markc.su/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a Thread Pool in C</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/threadpool_c/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 09:09:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/threadpool_c/</guid><description>Table of Contents&amp;nbsp;¶ Why a thread pool in C? Basic Layout Implementation Work Node Thread Pool Functions t_pool_init thread_work_loop t_pool_pop_work t_pool_destroy t_process_count Using the thread pool Final words Why a thread pool in C?&amp;nbsp;¶ For the past few weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a Discord bot library written in C called Disco-C. It allows for people to easily write their own Discord bots all in C.</description></item><item><title>React.js Games</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/react_games/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 09:14:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/react_games/</guid><description>React.js Games&amp;nbsp;¶ Recently I was at a hackathon (StartHack 22) and there I did a lot of frontend for the app we produced. I told myself there I&amp;rsquo;ll not write another line of Javascript or CSS for the weeks to come, because I had enough frontend for the time being. Then came the weekend and some people were playing Minesweeper on my Discord bot Lecturfier. The problem with Minesweeper on Discord is though, that the playing field is simply one big field of spoiler-tagged characters, meaning there is no way to actually flag bombs and there&amp;rsquo;s no way for the bot to know if you won or lost.</description></item><item><title>3D Raycasting</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/raycasting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 08:11:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/raycasting/</guid><description>Becoming a Coding Train Fanboy&amp;nbsp;¶ Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been binging a lot of YouTube again and for a while now I&amp;rsquo;ve been recommended The Coding Train videos, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never cared enough to open one of his 40min videos, until a week ago when I discovered how great his coding projects are. Upon watching the introduction of one of his approximating Pi videos I decided it would be fun to try and code the program, before watching the video.</description></item><item><title>Learning the Nimble Nim</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/learning_nim/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 14:38:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/learning_nim/</guid><description>Table of Contents&amp;nbsp;¶ What is Nim? Why? The Surprises Variables Switch Cases For Loops Procedures Arrays Objects Conclusion What is Nim?&amp;nbsp;¶ Nim does a good job explaining what it is in a short way on their website:
Nim is a statically typed compiled systems programming language. It combines successful concepts from mature languages like Python, Ada and Modula.
But that quote only covers a tiny portion of what Nim really is.</description></item><item><title>Making the Hangman Solver Faster</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/hangman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 18:45:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/hangman/</guid><description>The What?&amp;nbsp;¶ A few years ago when I was starting with Python we used to sometimes play little hangman games in class. I thought it to be a really good practice to write a little program, that could tell me what character I should guess next. That&amp;rsquo;s where I started with my hangman solver. I can put in the word I&amp;rsquo;m looking for, the characters that are not allowed and the language (English or German) it should search words for.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Hugo</title><link>https://markc.su/posts/getting_started/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 18:24:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://markc.su/posts/getting_started/</guid><description>Welcome&amp;nbsp;¶ Welcome to the grand opening of my new website. This is the very first post on here.
This website is mainly to test out new stuff in the direction of web development, as that is a direction I don&amp;rsquo;t currently have a lot of experience with. Additionally, a plan I have in mind is to write quick summaries for topics I&amp;rsquo;m currently learning about. This would be useful for myself to look back at when learning for exams and it might even be interesting for some people to read about the topics.</description></item></channel></rss>